<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Layout on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/layout/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Layout on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/layout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A LaTeX template for my dissertation</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2009-05-11-a-latex-template-for-my-dissertation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 16:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2009-05-11-a-latex-template-for-my-dissertation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the recent weeks I have spent a lot of time to polish the draft of my dissertation with the help of LaTeX. In this article, I would like to share the packages I used. This list of packages comes close to a template, but you must still decide which package you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, I wanted to have a &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/PdfTeX&#34;&gt;pdfTeX&lt;/a&gt;-compliant document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. KOMA Script&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;documentclass[DIV=calc, 11pt, parskip=half]{scrreprt}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basis for my dissertation is the &lt;em&gt;report&lt;/em&gt; class of KOMA Script. I will change this to &lt;em&gt;book&lt;/em&gt; once I come close to printing, but for reviewing &lt;em&gt;report&lt;/em&gt; is fine. It is intended for European formats (A4 is the default paper size).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I let LaTeX compute the page margins (DIV=calc). This is the easiest way to guarantee good readability for different font sizes. The basic idea is that a certain number of letters per line is optimal for reading. This leads to rather large margins but good readability. The font size is specified with &lt;em&gt;11pt&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;parskip=half&lt;/em&gt; makes LaTeX separate paragraphs with space between them (indenting is the default).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Language-specific packages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage[english]{babel}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The babel package allows you to set the language(s) of the document. This effects a lot of things, hyphenation for instance, but also section headings like &lt;em&gt;Table of contents&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;References&lt;/em&gt;, which are changed according to the language specified. You can even have multiple languages in one document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage[utf8]{inputenc}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everybody outside of English-speaking countries runs into problems with special characters like the German Umlauts (&amp;auml;&amp;ouml;&amp;uuml;&amp;Auml;&amp;Ouml;&amp;Uuml;). To make LaTeX process and display these special characters correctly, you need the &lt;strong&gt;inputenc&lt;/strong&gt; package. It takes the document&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Character_encoding&#34;&gt;character encoding&lt;/a&gt; as argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage[T1]{fontenc}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This package makes LaTeX load a new, extended fonts with all these European accented characters. So they are displayed nicely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Graphics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage{graphicx}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to include graphics in your document, you will need one package for this. I use the &lt;strong&gt;graphicx&lt;/strong&gt; package, which provides the command &lt;em&gt;includegraphics&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage[small, bf, up, hang]{caption}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The default captions of LaTeX do not look very appealing, since they use the exact same font as the normal text. The &lt;strong&gt;caption&lt;/strong&gt; package lets you choose a different layout for captions, as given in the package options. &lt;em&gt;small&lt;/em&gt; means that a smaller font size is used, &lt;em&gt;bf&lt;/em&gt; refers to the caption label which is made bold faced, &lt;em&gt;up&lt;/em&gt; means regular upright font and &lt;em&gt;hang&lt;/em&gt; refers to the way how multiple lines are dealt with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage[percent]{overpic}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another problem is using text with graphs. If you design graphs with a program, you will almost certainly have a different font and &amp;emdash; depending on the figure size &amp;emdash; a different font size compared to the rest of your document. One solution for this is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PSfrag&#34;&gt;PSfrag&lt;/a&gt; package, with the big disadvantage that it does not work for &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/PdfTeX&#34;&gt;pdfTeX&lt;/a&gt;. The &lt;strong&gt;overpic&lt;/strong&gt; package is compatible with pdfTeX, you have to specify the coordinates where LaTeX constructs are inserted. I prefer the &lt;em&gt;percent&lt;/em&gt; option, where relative coordinates are used, in case of image scaling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Maths&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dissertation does not contain a lot of mathematical formula. But there are some elements to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage{amsmath}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amsmath package provides a lot of commands and environments for maths. Just loading the package makes mathematic terms look nicer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage{nicefrac}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The normal way to typeset fractions is with a horizontal fraction line. This uses a lot of space. The &lt;strong&gt;nicefrac&lt;/strong&gt; package provides the &lt;em&gt;nicefrac&lt;/em&gt; command, which creates a fraction with diagonal fraction line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage{units}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most documents use either a full space between number and unit (2.3 N) or no space at all (2.3N). Both looks nasty, a half space is the optically pleasing distance (2.3&amp;thinsp;N). The units package provides the commands unit[2.3]{N} and unitfrac[4.3]{Nm}{s} for nicely set units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Tables&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting large tables with LaTeX is a pain and one area where &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wysiwyg&#34;&gt;WYSIWYG&lt;/a&gt; typesetting programs offer a much more intuitive approach. But it works with LaTeX as well, if you know the tricks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage{booktabs}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people tend to draw all conceivable lines in tables. But this is not necessary, as the elements of a table are already aligned. In books, you will therefore find only three horizontal lines per table, one above the heading, one below, and a last one at the bottom of the table. The booktabs package provides these three lines or rules (British English) as &lt;em&gt;toprule&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;midrule&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;bottomrule&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;usepackage{multirow}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;usepackage{rotating}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, you will need text which spans multiple rows. Since space is precious, I have used rotated text in these cases, requiring the packages &lt;strong&gt;rotating&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;multirow&lt;/strong&gt;. The rotating package provides the &lt;em&gt;sideways&lt;/em&gt; environment for the task I described, but you can also easily rotate a whole table by using the &lt;em&gt;sidewaystable&lt;/em&gt; instead of the &lt;em&gt;table&lt;/em&gt; environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Bibliography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the big strengths of LaTeX is the handling of bibliographic data with &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BibTeX&#34;&gt;BibTeX&lt;/a&gt;. The prerequisite for using BibTeX is to organize your bibliography in a database. There are numerous options available, I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.citeulike.org&#34;&gt;CiteULike&lt;/a&gt;, an online solution. It takes some effort to post all your read articles, books, and conference proceedings in there, but the merit is a database which you can easily integrate in any of your publications. All you need to know is a key for each publication, e.g. AuthorYear. But BibTeX has also some drawbacks, therefore, a lot of LaTeX packages exist to provide an easier interface to BibTeX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;_usepackage[style=apa, noremoteinfo,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hyperref=auto,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bibencoding=inputenc,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;refsection=chapter]{biblatex}_&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the more recent developments is the &lt;strong&gt;biblatex&lt;/strong&gt; package, which aims to provide a full LaTeX interface to the bibliography. It is compatible with the &lt;strong&gt;hyperref&lt;/strong&gt; package, allows section bibliographies and everything else you could ever want. I use the APA style for citations and the bibliography (&lt;em&gt;style=apa&lt;/em&gt;), the option &lt;em&gt;noremoteinfo&lt;/em&gt; prevents LaTeX from printing DOI links and other nasty stuff in the bibliography, &lt;em&gt;bibencoding=inputenc&lt;/em&gt; sets the character encoding of the bibliography to the same value as specified in the package &lt;strong&gt;inputenc&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;refsection=chapter&lt;/em&gt; automatically creates section-wise bibliographies on the chapter level of the document.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the document, I use &lt;em&gt;parencite{key}&lt;/em&gt; for citations in parenthesis and &lt;em&gt;textcite{key}&lt;/em&gt; for citations that are part of the text. And &lt;em&gt;printbibliography&lt;/em&gt; prints the bibliography exactly at this place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Miscallenious&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage{microtype}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without understanding the details of microtypography, just using this package improves certain typographic features of your document (ever heard of character protrusion or font expansion?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;usepackage{xspace}&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever you define a text macro with &lt;em&gt;newcommand&lt;/em&gt;, e.g. for typesetting special terms, you will encounter the problem of a missing space after the macro. Therefore, you need an intelligent space (&lt;em&gt;xspace&lt;/em&gt;) in the macro definition, which occurs in normal text but not at the end of the sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ten Reasons to Typeset Scientific Texts in LaTeX</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-12-15-10-reasons-to-write-scientific-texts-with-latex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2008 22:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-12-15-10-reasons-to-write-scientific-texts-with-latex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever you write a report in a scientific environment, a Master thesis, a journal publication, or a dissertation, you have the choice which text editing tool to use. It comes usually down to Word vs. LaTeX. I will now argue why you should use LaTeX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Focus on content, not layout.&lt;/strong&gt; When editing your LaTeX document with the editing program of your choice you can focus on the content. You need to provide some logical markup (this is a section, this is a reference citation), but that is easy to learn. Most Word users tend to focus on layout instead of content and structure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Free.&lt;/strong&gt; LaTeX is completely free. Just download it and use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No crashes.&lt;/strong&gt; Increasing page numbers and complexity sometimes leads to Word documents that crash and can not be reopened. Imagine this happening one day before you have to submit your thesis!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reproducible results.&lt;/strong&gt; When using more advanced features like automatic table of contents, internal references, or automatic managing of bibliographies, Word tends to do changes at unforeseen times, destroying the reformatting work of hours. This will not happen with LaTeX, if you got it to do something it will not change back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better look.&lt;/strong&gt; There are a lot of rules how to create documents that look good. It&amp;#8217;s about margins, aspect ratios of text columns, connecting certain letters and many other things experienced typesetters know. And LaTeX will use these rules, if you let it! So the results just look far better than those created with Word.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better layout of equations.&lt;/strong&gt; Same as above goes for mathematical equations. They just look better. Try this in Word: &lt;div id=&#34;attachment_1854&#34; style=&#34;width: 186px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption alignnone&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mwellner.de/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/formel.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.mwellner.de/wp-content/uploads/2009/09/formel.png&#34; alt=&#34;Mathematische Formel, gesetzt mit LaTeX&#34; title=&#34;Mathematische Formel&#34; width=&#34;176&#34; height=&#34;50&#34; class=&#34;size-full wp-image-1854&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Mathematische Formel, gesetzt mit LaTeX
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Floating environments.&lt;/strong&gt; In LaTeX, you can provide figures or tables and let the system decide where exactly to put them. So there are no empty areas when you add a sentence on a page with an image.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Units.&lt;/strong&gt; When you need to report a measure with a unit, you may either write 9.2m or 9.2 m, both looks strange. The solution is an unbreakable half space, like 9.2&amp;thinsp;m. And the LaTeX package units provides an easy command for that and does the typesetting for you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reference management.&lt;/strong&gt; As a scientist you read lots of papers which you may want to use in your scientific text. I used also once a Word-Endnote combination, but was not satisfied at all. It was impossible to change the location of the references list, since Word would redo my brave attempts to push it to a different space and looking for references needed a lot of clicks. In contrast, LaTeX comes with BibTeX, where you give a key to each reference and can easily cite it with that key. You can also change the way you want to cite, from numbers like [3] to Author names like (Rondel and McDouglas, 1992).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Packages for all kinds of special problems.&lt;/strong&gt; There is a multitude of free packages which solve all kind of problems. Want nicer figure captions? Need to typeset chemical formula? Want to cite in APA style? No problem, there are packages around for that.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>