<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/en/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 21:39:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Theater Production and Actor Database</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2017/01/theater-production-and-actor-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 21:39:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2017/01/theater-production-and-actor-database/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Currently, I am working on a hobby project, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mwellner/mwtdb&#34;&gt;theater production and actor database&lt;/a&gt;
(mwtdb for short). It is visible on GitHub and open source.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements&#34;&gt;Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I want to create is something similar to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/&#34;&gt;IMDb&lt;/a&gt;, which focuses on
movies, TV and celebreties, but for amateur theater. A very basic version will contain actors, directors and technicians,
contributing to productions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From a technical point of view, I will create a web application, using &lt;a href=&#34;https://angular.io/&#34;&gt;Angular&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href=&#34;https://neo4j.com/&#34;&gt;Neo4j&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Graph_database&#34;&gt;graph database&lt;/a&gt;. The hope is that
a graphical representation of the data at hand is better suited for retrieving the right data for a particular view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;first-steps&#34;&gt;First Steps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have used &lt;a href=&#34;https://cli.angular.io/&#34;&gt;Angular CLI&lt;/a&gt; to initialize my application. &lt;a href=&#34;https://v4-alpha.getbootstrap.com/&#34;&gt;Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;
will be my front-end framework, along with &lt;a href=&#34;https://ng-bootstrap.github.io/&#34;&gt;ng-bootstrap&lt;/a&gt; for some interactive components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first Angular components were &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mwellner/mwtdb/blob/master/src/app/people/people.component.ts&#34;&gt;people&lt;/a&gt;
(actors, directors) and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mwellner/mwtdb/blob/master/src/app/productions/productions.component.ts&#34;&gt;productions&lt;/a&gt;,
showing a list of existing items and allowing to add more entries. For the graph database, I have created a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mwellner/mwtdb/blob/master/src/app/database.service.ts&#34;&gt;database service&lt;/a&gt;, which implements a few basic queries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Service Worker Experiments</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2016/11/service-worker-experiments/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 15:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2016/11/service-worker-experiments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am currently experimenting with service workers (see
&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/API/Service_Worker_API/Using_Service_Workers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Using
Service Workers&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/web/fundamentals/getting-started/primers/service-workers&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Service
Workers: an Introduction&lt;/a&gt;). One scenario is to provide mock data when no connection to an external service is available.
And by theory, service workers should be able to intercept any request made by the website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there is one exception. If you fetch data with &lt;a href=&#34;http://api.jquery.com/jquery.ajax/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;jQuery.ajax()&lt;/a&gt;
function and use &lt;em&gt;async: false&lt;/em&gt;, the service worker will not be able to intercept any of those requests. I am not quite sure
about the underlying cause, but wanted to share my findings.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Technical Summit 2016 in Darmstadt</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2016/11/technical-summit-2016-in-darmstadt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Nov 2016 22:33:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2016/11/technical-summit-2016-in-darmstadt/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Soon, I will attend the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.microsoft.com/germany/technical-summit/default.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Technical Summit 2016&lt;/a&gt;, which will take place from Dec 6 to 8 in Darmstadt. This is my first conference for my new employer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.conweaver.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ConWeaver&lt;/a&gt;), where I am working pretty much along the same lines as for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.comparis.ch&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Comparis&lt;/a&gt;, meaning front-end development with HTML, CSS and JavaScript and its many derivatives (&lt;a href=&#34;http://sass-lang.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sass&lt;/a&gt;, LESS, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.typescriptlang.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/a&gt;). A new challenge is &lt;a href=&#34;https://angular.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Angular&lt;/a&gt;, which has recently reached version 2 and comes with a nodejs-based workflow and with mostly alpha-staged tools around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it is definitely good to get some insights on existing and new technologies in the quickly evolving world of web development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a data-flickr-embed=&#34;true&#34; href=&#34;https://www.flickr.com/photos/mwellner/32727033490/in/album-72157677198199094/&#34; title=&#34;MW_20160911_2589&#34;&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://c1.staticflickr.com/1/770/32727033490_87a429a509_b.jpg&#34; width=&#34;1024&#34; height=&#34;683&#34; alt=&#34;MW_20160911_2589&#34;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the keynotes, there are up to 6 parallel sessions going on. Some sessions I fancy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;apts-cybercrime-cyber-attacks-warfare-and-threats-exposed&#34;&gt;APTs: Cybercrime, Cyber Attacks, Warfare and Threats Exposed&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this session, see a live demonstration of the tools and techniques used by cybercriminals and cyber warriors today. We demonstrate what the threat-landscape looks like today, how the attackers penetrate your network, how they make their attacks undetectable from conventional antivirus and evade IDS solutions. We show how they expand their initial foothold to complete domain compromise and finally how they obtain their goal and infiltrate your data. A must see awareness session if you want to understand the threats of today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;give-your-apps-a-human-side-through-machine-learning&#34;&gt;Give your apps a human side through Machine Learning&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The future of machine learning will be invisible; it will exist, you will use machine learning in your everyday lives, and you wouldn’t even know it. Now is a good time to start integrating amazing machine learning features into your applications, as they become integral to our society. The Cognitive Services APIs are practically invisible. You don’t need to build your own complex algorithms to make your application smarter and more powerful. Cognitive Services is a set of ready-made machine learning APIs that allow you to breath intelligence into your application using only simple HTTP calls. In this talk, you will be introduced to the Cognitive Services APIs and see how you can use them to transform your application. This is about the power of machine learning and computer vision at the end of an API call.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;css-flexbox-the-future-of-user-interface-design&#34;&gt;CSS Flexbox: The Future of User Interface Design&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite topic&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;introduction-to-react-js&#34;&gt;Introduction to React.js&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;React.js is a game changer for web applications.Made by Facebook for slick, modern user interfaces and able to handleheavy data lifting with brilliant performance, it&amp;#8217;s revolutionised howdevelopers all around the world build their apps.Let&amp;#8217;s explore what makes it special and the core concepts to get you upto speed with the new hot thing in JavaScript!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;progressive-web-apps-the-web-gets-more-native-and-microsoft-is-part-of-it&#34;&gt;Progressive Web Apps: The web gets more native and Microsoft is part of it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I hope some of you out there will join the fun here in beautiful Darmstadt!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fighting with JSON</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2016/11/fighting-with-json/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2016 16:47:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2016/11/fighting-with-json/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In my current project, I had to deal with huge JSON files, which contain the order and properties of our layout elements.
For CSS styling purposes, I had to move one particular array item to the end, create a new object and move all existing
elements inside of that new object. This was tedious work when I did that manually.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided to develop a little C# Console application, taking care of that for me. After a few hours I managed to
complete it &amp;ndash; and here are my learnings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;library&#34;&gt;Library&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newtonsoft.com/json&#34;&gt;JSON.Net&lt;/a&gt;, which is the de-facto standard for .NET.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;parsing&#34;&gt;Parsing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with JSON is that you can get different types (array, object). Hence, we do not want to be too type-specific
to be able to cast to the expected type. And we have the wonderful &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/de-de/library/dd264741.aspx&#34;&gt;dynamic&lt;/a&gt;
type declaration, which prevents compile-time type checks. So we use &lt;em&gt;dynamic&lt;/em&gt; as long in the line as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
dynamic json = JsonConvert.DeserializeObject(jsonString)
dynamic element = json.GetValue(&#34;Element&#34;);
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;working-with-elements&#34;&gt;Working with Elements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found two techniques for selecting a particular element in the JSON tree. You can either use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newtonsoft.com/json/help/html/SelectToken.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SelectToken&lt;/a&gt;, which works best for nested objects. Alternatively you can also use &lt;a href=&#34;https://msdn.microsoft.com/de-de/library/bb397906.aspx&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LINQ queries&lt;/a&gt; like FirstOrDefault().&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To remove or add items, I converted to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newtonsoft.com/json/help/html/t_newtonsoft_json_linq_jarray.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;JArray&lt;/a&gt;, which provides Add() and Remove() functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One important thing is to clone elements, which are inserted at a different position. Use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.newtonsoft.com/json/help/html/M_Newtonsoft_Json_Linq_JToken_DeepClone.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;DeepClone()&lt;/a&gt; to get your new element.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After falling in the trap of quickly hand-editing a large JSON file, I developed a small command-line tool to do the modifications I needed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2016/11/angular/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 22:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2016/11/angular/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After my first week at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.conweaver.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ConWeaver&lt;/a&gt;, I got a first impression of the search framework and the technology used. The hot topic in the moment is &lt;a href=&#34;https://angular.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Angular&lt;/a&gt;, which is a web application framework. In contrast to other server-side frameworks, the application logic is on the client (browser). This is a major trend now, aiming at &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/web/progressive-web-apps/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Progressive Web Apps&lt;/a&gt;, which are as quick and responsive as native applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To work with Angular, I need to understand the entire ecosystem which has evolved for developing with Angular. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.typescriptlang.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/a&gt; is used as an improved version of JavaScript, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;npm&lt;/a&gt; for packaging and tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One tool I can heavily recommend is &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;. It works on Windows and Linux, has built-in &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; functionality and is just perfect for working with a web project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I have found the Linux environment slightly easier to use. On Windows, some Node packages needed to be installed globally with appropriate PATH settings, what was not quite intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are still a lot of things to discover and learn out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Student Initiatives</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2002/09/student-initiatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2002 20:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2002/09/student-initiatives/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Friday, most of the students organizations presented themselves in Squires Student Center. Interested to get involved in
something I entered the room. It was packed with people, you could hear music playing from one corner, and a babble of voices
was in the air. The organizations were organized in long rows of tables, with every organization only having two meters to
present their material.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I went through, drowned in the many possibilities and smiles. A large part were those three-Greek-letter-fraternities
and sororities. Like Pi Omega Alpha. I didn&amp;rsquo;t quite understand the point in them. Some had social welfare programs, but
one common objective was to organize parties and more private events where alcohol was available. Another number of clubs
dealed with religious issues. The Whitnesses of Jehova not to forget. A large part of orgs were about social welfare, what
really meant service for other people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some funny things also caught my attention. The Holerin Hokies are people who attend sport events and cry for VT (Virginia Tech).
The benefit of it are T-Shirts, reserved places and maybe even free access to some events.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day of Mindfulness</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2002/02/day-of-mindfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Feb 2002 09:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2002/02/day-of-mindfulness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I visited a speech given by a Buddhist monk on mindfulness. He was a lank person with bushy fair eye brows. He wore the traditional orange garment and he was shaven-headed. Born in California he experienced the Vietnam war in a state of stonedness far off the battle fields. On a subsequent journey he travelled to Asia and decided after a while to join Buddhism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His way of talking was deliberate and calm, his hands rested on his lap for the whole time. Only his deep eyes were wandering through the room, fixing many persons for a while before wandering to the next. He explained the bases of Buddhism, in relation to American everyday life. Many things I knew already, but I had forgotten them and was delighted to see them restrengthened. I was thinking mainly on Erich Fromms &amp;#8220;The Art of Loving&amp;#8221;, especially the final chapter when Fromm gave some advise on personal advancement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main aspect was the awareness of the present. Not to sway into future or past with their many grievances, hopes and anxieties. Just be (in contraste to the popular shoe slogan). An interesting comparison was that of the very word &amp;#8220;human being&amp;#8221;. With todays fast-paced life, humans tend to become &amp;#8220;human doings&amp;#8221;, meaning that their mind is always focussed on doing something, and not on the moment. In order to train this kind of awareness, he suggested meditation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow there will be a whole day of mindfulness, meaning three meditation and discussion sessions with him. The first one starts at eight in the morning, so for the first time since our home volleyball tournament I will have to get up early. I am really looking forward to the whole thing, since I am feeling a little bit unbalanced in the last weeks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>