<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graduation on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/graduation/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graduation on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/graduation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ETH Graduation Ceremony</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2010-01-18-eth-graduation-ceremony/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2010 23:39:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2010-01-18-eth-graduation-ceremony/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last chapter, the very last on my way to PhD &amp;ndash; the ceremonial handover of the certificate. The Scherrer lecture hall was decorated festively, as were the new doctors. The ETH Big Band performed with a brassy ensemble, blaring jubilation. Every one of us then would walk there, receiving the certificate from the rector. A few words, smiling towards the photographer, again to the rector, &amp;#8220;all the best on your way&amp;#8221;. The same procedure for about 150 persons, non-stop certificates. Believe me, it&amp;#8217;s nothing special. I had to return to my company in the evening, finishing something, caught in my new job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slowly my view on the ETH time is becoming transfigured, another station passed. But from here the next step is unclear, I am completely free. Enterprise, projects, family, Germany, Switzerland, Austria &amp;ndash; it&amp;#8217;s all open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The certificate is well-designed. The ETH logo is embossed, fine red lines draw through the area on the right; and the slim ETH font gives the title area an austere elegance. I will keep it safe and not put it on my wall, because I don&amp;#8217;t want people to consult me for physical ailments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>