<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Graphical on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/graphical/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Graphical on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/graphical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>LabVIEW revisited</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2011-05-19-labview-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2011 22:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2011-05-19-labview-revisited/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the early days of my time as PhD student, I had the forced pleasure to work with &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/LabVIEW&#34;&gt;LabVIEW&lt;/a&gt;. In contrast to text-based programming languages (the vast majority), LabVIEW uses a graphical approach, pleasing the aesthetic mind, but looking extremely crammed and confusing for larger projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my recent project, LabVIEW caught me again. Luckily we use it in combination with a scripting language, which implements the device logic, while LabVIEW is confined to the user interface. This makes it bearable, but very repetitive. And repetitive means mouse clicks and movements &amp;ndash; a lot of mouse clicks and movements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event structure caused me also a lot of pain. Back in 2005 I really wanted it, a piece of code that is only executed when the user clicks a button or changes a setting. The alternative is polling, asking for the value of the user control again and again. Anyways, they introduced the event structure, but you can&amp;#8217;t place it just somewhere. It made my program block, it didn&amp;#8217;t work at all, was never executed &amp;ndash; all that kind of problems you run into as programmer. But I solved it and made it work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>