<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Submit on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/submit/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Submit on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/submit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>I am going slightly mad</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-04-10-i-am-going-slightly-mad/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2008 18:57:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-04-10-i-am-going-slightly-mad/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I resubmitted my manuscript to the journal of my choice. The review process has taken a long time, they were almost satisfied with my paper last time but still required a lot of changes to publish it. So now, it is the third or fourth time, I am resubmitting these pages. There are a lot of changes to the manuscript and I learned, what a post-hoc Tukey test was. So here we go again&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; This paper describes evaluation experiments for visual and auditory feedback in a virtual obstacle walking scenario. Two studies with healthy subjects were carried out using the actuated gait orthosis Lokomat. Controlled factors for the visual feedback experiment were three different perspectives and 2D/3D vision. In the auditory feedback experiment, controlled factors were rhythmic distance feedback and gradual foot clearance feedback. For the visual and auditory feedback experiments, outcome was assessed with task-specific performance parameters and questionnaires. Results for visual feedback indicate that the chosen side perspective is superior to behind and ego perspectives. It is also shown that 3D vision does not reduce the number of obstacle hits compared to 2D vision. Furthermore, it is demonstrated that adding continuous auditory feedback made subjects walk faster compared to the exclusive use of visual feedback. Sujects rated auditory distance feedback as more helpful than auditory foot clearance feedback. Therefore, we suggest to use the side perspective and auditory feedback on obstacle distance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What has happened before&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resubmission on January 24, 2008&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mwellner.de/2007/08/29/paper-submission/&#34;&gt;Original submission on August 29, 2007&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>