<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Www on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/en/categories/www/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Www on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/en/categories/www/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2016/11/angular/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 22:58:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/en/2016/11/angular/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After my first week at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.conweaver.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ConWeaver&lt;/a&gt;, I got a first impression of the search framework and the technology used. The hot topic in the moment is &lt;a href=&#34;https://angular.io/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Angular&lt;/a&gt;, which is a web application framework. In contrast to other server-side frameworks, the application logic is on the client (browser). This is a major trend now, aiming at &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/web/progressive-web-apps/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Progressive Web Apps&lt;/a&gt;, which are as quick and responsive as native applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To work with Angular, I need to understand the entire ecosystem which has evolved for developing with Angular. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.typescriptlang.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;TypeScript&lt;/a&gt; is used as an improved version of JavaScript, &lt;a href=&#34;https://nodejs.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Node.js&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.npmjs.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;npm&lt;/a&gt; for packaging and tooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One tool I can heavily recommend is &lt;a href=&#34;https://code.visualstudio.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Visual Studio Code&lt;/a&gt;. It works on Windows and Linux, has built-in &lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Git&lt;/a&gt; functionality and is just perfect for working with a web project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I have found the Linux environment slightly easier to use. On Windows, some Node packages needed to be installed globally with appropriate PATH settings, what was not quite intuitive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But there are still a lot of things to discover and learn out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>