<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Www on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/www/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Www on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/www/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Implementing simple ajax show/hide effects with cakePHP</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2010-04-15-implementing-simple-ajax-showhide-effects-with-cakephp/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2010 09:56:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2010-04-15-implementing-simple-ajax-showhide-effects-with-cakephp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are quite some tutorials on ajax effects out there [1, 2], but most were too complex for my needs. I simply wanted an enhanced index page for projects, which shows some details for each project and more on demand with a sliding effect. So here is what my solution looks like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used cakePHP 1.3 RC3. I assume that you have a running cakePHP application with an index view of your main objects of concern. You also need to download the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.prototypejs.org/&#34;&gt;prototype&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://script.aculo.us/&#34;&gt;scriptaculous&lt;/a&gt; scripts and put all js-files into your /app/webroot/js folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Activating ajax&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your default layout, you have to include the links to the prototype and scriptaculous scripts in the head section of the template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre name=&#34;code&#34; class=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- file app/views/layout/default.ctp --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;head&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;!-- existing head settings --&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;?php
    echo $javascript-&gt;link(&#39;prototype&#39;);
    echo $javascript-&gt;link(&#39;scriptaculous.js?load=effects&#39;);
    ?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/head&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You also need to activate the AJAX and Javascript helpers in the controller where you want to use it. I prefered to update the app controller, which enables the helpers for all controllers. Your app controller (usually at app/app_controller.php, create if necessary) should include the ajax and javascript helpers like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre name=&#34;code&#34; class=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- file app/app_controller.php --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;?php
class AppController extends Controller {
    var $helpers = array(&#39;Html&#39;, &#39;Form&#39;, &#39;Ajax&#39;, &#39;Javascript&#39;);
}
?&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In your view&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In your view you can now include id-marked divs and ajax links to control the visibility of these divs. Assuming that your model is named Project, you need to update your index view at /app/views/project/index.ctp. I use two table rows for that. The first row contains the project name, the ajax links for showing/hiding details, and the actions. The second row is invisible at first (display:none) and contains the div which is controlled by the ajax links. To my knowledge it is not possible to hide/show entire table rows, therefore the second row is rendered empty at first. But it looks quite nice with the default alternate background color for table rows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real trick here was to leave the second argument for the ajax link empty, linking to the same page. All other examples had links to sub pages implemented there what seemed too complex for my wishes. Of course, this implementation means that the entire content is loaded every time. For huge amounts of data this could be a performance issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre name=&#34;code&#34; class=&#34;php&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;!-- file app/views/project/index.ctp --&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;table cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34;&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;th&gt;&amp;lt;?php echo $paginator-&gt;sort(&#39;name&#39;);?&gt;&amp;lt;/th&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;th class=&#34;actions&#34;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;?php __(&#39;Actions&#39;);?&gt;&amp;lt;/th&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;?php
$i = 0;
foreach ($projects as $project):
    $id = $project[&#39;Project&#39;][&#39;id&#39;];
    $i++;
?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;?php echo $project[&#39;Project&#39;][&#39;name&#39;];?&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;?php 
        // define string for div id
        $div_string = &#39;project_fold_&#39;.$i;

    // create ajax link which shows project details
    echo $ajax-&gt;link(
        &#39;show details&#39;,
        &#39;&#39;, 
        array( 
        &#39;update&#39; =&gt; $div_string, 
        &#39;loading&#39; =&gt; &#39;Effect.Appear(\&#39;&#39;.$div_string.&#39;\&#39;)&#39;,
        )
    );

    // create ajax link which hides project details
    echo $ajax-&gt;link(
        &#39;hide details&#39;,
        &#39;&#39;, 
        array( 
        &#39;update&#39; =&gt; $div_string, 
        &#39;loading&#39; =&gt; &#39;Effect.Fade(\&#39;&#39;.$div_string.&#39;\&#39;)&#39;,
        )
    );
    ?&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;td class=&#34;actions&#34;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;?php echo $html-&gt;link(__(&#39;View&#39;, true), array(&#39;action&#39;=&gt;&#39;view&#39;, $id));?&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;?php echo $html-&gt;link(__(&#39;Edit&#39;, true), array(&#39;action&#39;=&gt;&#39;edit&#39;, $id));?&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;?php echo $html-&gt;link(
            __(&#39;Delete&#39;, true), 
            array( &#39;action&#39;=&gt;&#39;delete&#39;, $id), 
            null, 
            sprintf(__(&#39;Are you sure you want to delete # %s?&#39;, true), $id));
        ?&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;td colspan=&#34;2&#34;&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;!-- display div which can be shown/hidden by ajax links --&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;?php echo $ajax-&gt;div($div_string, array(&#39;style&#39; =&gt; &#39;display:none&#39;)); ?&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;!-- project details --&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;&amp;lt;?php echo __(&#39;Project details&#39;);?&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;dl&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;dt&amp;gt;&amp;lt;?php echo __(&#39;Description&#39;);?&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/dt&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;dd&amp;gt;&amp;lt;?php echo $project[&#39;Project&#39;][&#39;description&#39;];?&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/dd&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;dt&amp;gt;&amp;lt;?php echo __(&#39;Budget&#39;);?&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/dt&amp;gt;
        &amp;lt;dd&amp;gt;&amp;lt;?php printf(&#34;%.2f&amp;thinsp;kCHF&#34;, $project[&#39;Project&#39;][&#39;budget&#39;]);?&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/dd&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/dl&amp;gt;

    &amp;lt;?php echo $ajax-&gt;divEnd($div_string); ?&amp;gt;
    &amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;?php endforeach; ?&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to go one step further, you can try to show/hide the ajax links as well. At first, only &lt;em&gt;show details&lt;/em&gt; is visible. When details are visible, only &lt;em&gt;hide details&lt;/em&gt; can be seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;References&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.reversefolds.com/articles/show/ajax&#34;&gt;AJAX cakePHP&lt;/a&gt;, ReverseFolds&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neues Weblog-System</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2009-08-05-neues-weblog-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2009 22:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2009-08-05-neues-weblog-system/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nachdem meine Tage an der ETH nunmehr gezählt sind, suchte ich nach einer neuen Heimat für mein Weblog, welches bisher vom &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.ethz.ch&#34;&gt;Weblog Service der ETH Zürich&lt;/a&gt; gehostet wurde. Es ist nun also auf dem von mir mitgenutzten Server, eine naheliegende Lösung. Das einzige Problem sind die vielen Sicherheitslücken in der Weblog-Software, welche unserem Systemadministrator Schweißperlen auf die Stirn treiben. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.php.net&#34;&gt;PHP&lt;/a&gt;, auf dem die Software &lt;a href=&#34;http://wordpress.org&#34;&gt;WordPress&lt;/a&gt; basiert, scheint sehr anfällig für alle möglichen Arten von Attacken zu sein. Aber warten wir ab, ob unser Server wirklich von Spammern gekapert wird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Auf jeden Fall ist mit diesem Weblog eine einheitliche Webpräsenz geschaffen, meine alte Homepage, die früher unter dieser Adresse zu erreichen war, hat ausgedient. Ich habe jedoch ausgewählte Inhalte übernommen, die Tagebücher aus Blacksburg findet ihr im Archiv (2002-03), eine Übersicht aller Lesungen auf den statischen Seiten (siehe &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mwellner.de/lesungen/&#34;&gt;Lesungen&lt;/a&gt;). Weblog und Homepage verschmelzen also zu einem Ganzen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ich bin auf jeden Fall gespannt, was ihr vom neuen Design haltet.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science and Weblogs</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-09-20-science-and-weblogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 13:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-09-20-science-and-weblogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my relentless search for articles in the field of rehabilitation robotics, I will publish some comments on excellent articles. With this I hope to help people who search relevant papers and also to find experts in the field for discussions and exchange. Everybody interested in the articles I found may take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.citeulike.org/user/wellnair&#34;&gt;my articles at CiteULike&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dissertation is about cooperative control strategies for the gait orthesis Lokomat. This field touches the following subject areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rehabilitation robotics (the big term),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control strategies in general,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variable structure control (swing and stance phase),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooperative control strategies (adaptive behaviour),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parameter identification (online if possible),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iterative learning,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patient model (so far the patient is seen as a disturbance) and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interface concept (in the end, therapists shall use all that with ease).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is an experiment, since scientists are so far not using weblogs as a means of exchange and discussion. At least I don&amp;#8217;t know of any. But since I like the idea of weblogs I try to make a start in that and use it for scientific purposes. I will publish in English, since that enhances chances to be found by scientists all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Authoring Issues</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-09-18-web-site-on-it-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2005 21:29:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-09-18-web-site-on-it-issues/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When rethinking the way blog links were assigned to languages, my first thought was to use flag symbols, as e.g. in Ulli&amp;#8217;s blog. But I surfed a little bit around and found a good site arguing against that. Here is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.tut.fi/~jkorpela/&#34;&gt;link to the main page&lt;/a&gt; covering many topics in web authoring and communication technology. The ones I scanned I found very interesting to read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the covered topics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.tut.fi/~jkorpela/flags.html&#34;&gt;Why you should not use a flag as a symbol of a language&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.tut.fi/~jkorpela/chars.html&#34;&gt;A tutorial on character code issues&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.tut.fi/~jkorpela/lingua-franca.html&#34;&gt;English &amp;#8211; the universal language of the web?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cs.tut.fi/~jkorpela/www.html&#34;&gt;Web authoring and surfing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Das Weblog als literarisches Medium</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-06-27-das-weblog-als-literarisches-medium/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2005 19:00:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-06-27-das-weblog-als-literarisches-medium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Momentan nutze ich die literarische Energie, die in mir fließt, zum Schreiben des elektronischen Tagebuchs (Weblog). Auf den ersten Blick mag dies seltsam erscheinen, ich möchte jedoch kurz erläutern, warum ich dieses Medium für geeignet halte, damit zu schreiben und zu veröffentlichen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ein Weblog ist &lt;strong&gt;frei zugänglich und kostenlos&lt;/strong&gt; zu nutzen (lesen). Damit kann jeder Interessierte mit einem Internetzugang die Inhalte lesen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ich kann von &lt;strong&gt;überall aus und ohne großen Aufwand veröffentlichen&lt;/strong&gt;, die Zwischenstufe des Verlegers entfällt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Weblogs bieten technische Möglichkeiten, die Bücher nicht besitzen, in erster Linie &lt;strong&gt;Verknüpfungen (Links)&lt;/strong&gt;. Damit kann ein bestimmter Typ von Texten unheimlich gut umgesetzt werden. Ich spreche von fragmentarischen, assoziativ geprägten Texten. Bei linear aufgebauten Texten (Romanen) machen Verknüpfungen keinen Sinn.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Das Einbinden von hochwertigen, farbigen &lt;strong&gt;Bildern&lt;/strong&gt; ist sehr gut möglich.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Das Weblog ist &lt;strong&gt;unmittelbar&lt;/strong&gt;, ich kann damit sehr schnell auf Entwicklungen reagieren und meinen Senf dazu geben.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ich möchte betonen, dass mein Weblog momentan eher faktisch als literarisch geprägt ist. Die vorgestellten Gedanken beziehen sich eher auf eine potenzielle Nutzung des Weblogs zur Veröffentlichung. Offen ist nach wie vor die Frage, ob sich dieses bisherige Weblog mit der Idee des literarischen Werkes verträgt, oder ob eine Trennung notwendig wäre.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Was ist RSS?</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-03-was-ist-rss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2005 22:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-03-was-ist-rss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ein wichtiger Grund für meinen Wechsel zu Serendipity war deren Unterstützung von RSS-Feeds. Doch was verbirgt sich hinter dieser weiteren dreibuchstabigen Abkürzung? Meine Suche führte mich zu &lt;a href=&#34;https://de.wikipedia.org/&#34;&gt;Wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;, einem vorzüglichen und frei verfügbaren Online-Lexikon. Dort fand ich einen &lt;a href=&#34;https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS&#34;&gt;umfangreichen Beitrag zum Thema&lt;/a&gt;. Doch für euch möchte ich hier einfach mal kurz zusammenfassen, wie ihr von dieser Technologie profitieren könnt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mit dem beliebten Webbrowser &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/de/firefox/products/&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; könnt ihr sogenannte &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/livebookmarks.html&#34;&gt;Live-Bookmarks&lt;/a&gt; anlegen. Damit könnt ihr den Link zu meinem Weblog nach rechts &amp;ldquo;aufklappen&amp;rdquo; und seht die Überschriften der aktuellsten Einträge. Besonders, wenn ihr ganz viele Lieblings-Weblogs habt, ist das praktisch. Denn dann könnt ihr sehr schnell überprüfen, ob sich was verändert hat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Darüber hinaus gehend, könnt ihr mit sogenannten News-Aggregator-Programmen (&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/News_aggregator&#34;&gt;englischer Wikipedia-Eintrag&lt;/a&gt;) die aktuellsten Einträge ausgewählter Weblogs oder anderer RSS-Feeds anbietender Seiten darstellen. Also nicht nur die Überschriften wie vorher, sondern quasi eine Seite mit allen neuen einträgen auf einen Blick.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Umstellung auf Serendipity</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-01-willkommen/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2005 00:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-01-willkommen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Liebe Blog-Leser,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;eine neue Ära ha begonnen, eine völlig andere Blog-Software verwaltet ab sofort meine Gedanken und sonstigen für die Öffentlichkeit bestimmten Dinge. Es handelt sich um Serendipity, und lässt sich einfach etwas besser verwalten als meine bisherige Weblog-Software. Außerdem sind jetzt RSS-Feeds problemlos möglich. Wenn euch das nichts sagt, ist das auch nicht so schlimm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Als nächstes werde ich probieren, die alten Einträge zu importieren, mal schauen, ob das klappt.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zurück ins ISDN-Zeitalter</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-03-17-zuruck-ins-isdn-zeitalter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2005 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-03-17-zuruck-ins-isdn-zeitalter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Von wegen früher war alles besser! In Bezug auf die Telekommunikation kann man das sicherlich nicht sagen. Wegen eines technischen Defektes im Bürgernetz mussten wir unseren Wohnungsserver wieder als ISDN-Verbindungs-Schnittstelle einrichten. Damit geraten zwei Aktionen wieder in den Vordergrund, die eigentlich absolut unnötig und zeitraubend sind: &lt;strong&gt;Einwahl&lt;/strong&gt; und &lt;strong&gt;Trennen&lt;/strong&gt;. Gelobt sei die Flatrate!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>