<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Virtual Reality on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/virtual-reality/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Virtual Reality on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/virtual-reality/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Journals for a publication of a rowing simulation study</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-11-12-journals-for-rowing-simulation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 16:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-11-12-journals-for-rowing-simulation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am recently searching for a journal to publish a study on audience pressure in our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sms.hest.ethz.ch/research/current-research-projects/robot-assisted-training-in-sports.html&#34;&gt;M³ Rowing Simulator&lt;/a&gt;. This is rather difficult due to the multidisciplinary approach taken. We use a simulator with &lt;em&gt;virtual reality&lt;/em&gt; technology, conduct a &lt;em&gt;sports study&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;em&gt;psychological effects&lt;/em&gt; to investigate the feeling of &lt;em&gt;presence&lt;/em&gt; in the simulator. It&amp;#8217;s easy to get one or two of these topics combined in a journal description, but four of them are just too much. But nevertheless I would like to share which journals I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mitpressjournals.org/pres&#34;&gt;Presence: Teleoperators and Virtual Environments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first academic journal for serious investigators of teleoperators and virtual environments, Presence is filled with stimulating material applicable to these advanced electromechanical and computer devices. Incorporating perspectives from physics to philosophy, Presence appeals to a wide audience &amp;#8211; particularly mechanical and electrical engineers concerned with teleoperators; those interested in virtual environments, including computer scientists, high-tech artists, and media people; and psychologists involved in the study of human-machine interfaces and sensorimotor/cognitive behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I published my first journal paper there. The review process was tough and long, but my paper was probably not that good in the beginning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liebertpub.com/products/product.aspx?pid=10&#34;&gt;CyberPsychology &amp;amp; Behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bimonthly peer-reviewed journal explores the impact of the Internet, multi-media and virtual reality on behavior and society. This journal is a &amp;#8220;must read&amp;#8221; for psychologists, psychiatrists, sociologists, educators, computer scientists, business executives and opinion-makers interested in the effects of interactive technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The focus is similar to that of Presence, although more on a general level with regards to interactive technologies and their implication on society.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computer Animation and Virtual Worlds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the advent of very powerful PCs and high-end graphics cards, there has been an incredible development in Virtual Worlds, real-time computer animation and simulation, games. But at the same time, new and cheaper Virtual Reality devices have appeared allowing an interaction with these real-time Virtual Worlds and even with real worlds through Augmented Reality. Three-dimensional characters, especially Virtual Humans are now of an exceptional quality, which allows to use them in the movie industry. But this is only a beginning, as with the development of Artificial Intelligence and Agent technology, these characters will become more and more autonomous and even intelligent. They will inhabit the Virtual Worlds in a Virtual Life together with animals and plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This would be good for a more general description of how we made the rowing scenario. Since we focused rather on conducting a sports study, this would probably not fit well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pip.sagepub.com/&#34;&gt;Journal of Sports Engineering and Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journal of Sports Engineering and Technology is the publication of choice for authors seeking to disseminate original research findings related to the development or application of technology in sports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High quality output from engineering focused research activity is presented where the objective of the work undertaken was to enhance user performance (fitness, skill, comfort, etc.), reduce incidence and severity of injury, increase participation rates, promote participation, or enhance the spectator experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They are quite new (one issue so far).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tandf.co.uk/journals/titles/02640414.asp&#34;&gt;Journal of Sports Sciences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journal of Sports Sciences publishes articles of a high standard on various aspects of the sports sciences covering a number of disciplinary bases, including anatomy, biochemistry, biomechanics, psychology, sociology, as well as ergonomics, kinanthropometry and other interdisciplinary perspectives. In addition to reports of research, review articles and book reviews are published. The emphasis of the Journal is on the human sciences, broadly defined, applied to sport and exercise. Besides experimental work in human responses to exercise, the subjects covered will include technologies such as the design of sports equipment and playing facilities, research in training, selection, performance prediction or modification, and stress reduction or manifestation. Manuscripts dealing with original investigations of exercise, validation of technological innovations in sport or comprehensive reviews of topics relevant to the scientific study of sport will be considered for publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journal presents research findings in the growing area of exercise and sports sciences to an international audience. The readership for this journal is varied and ranges from academic research workers to professionals in recreation, sports coaching and training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.humankinetics.com/jsep/journalAbout.cfm&#34;&gt;Journal of Sport &amp;amp; Exercise Psychology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journal of Sport &amp;amp; Exercise Psychology (JSEP) publishes research articles by leading world scholars that explore the interactions between psychology and exercise and sport performance, editorials about contemporary issues in the field, abstracts of current research on sport and exercise psychology, and book reviews. JSEP is an official publication of the North American Society for the Psychology of Sport and Physical Activity (NASPSPA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springer.com/new+%26+forthcoming+titles+(default)/journal/12283&#34;&gt;Sports Engineering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sports Engineering is an international journal publishing original papers on the application of engineering and science to sport. The journal intends to fill the niche area which lies between classical engineering and sports science and aims to bridge the gap between the analysis of the equipment and of the athlete. Areas of interest include the mechanics and dynamics of sport, the analysis of movement, instrumentation, equipment design, surface interaction, materials and modelling. These topics may be applied to technology in almost any sport. The journal will be of particular interest to Engineering, Physics, Mathematics and Sports Science Departments and will act as a forum where research, industry and the sports sector can exchange knowledge and innovative ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Review on Latency</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-06-30-review-on-latency/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2008 14:38:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-06-30-review-on-latency/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With virtual environments and realism being the central topic of my dissertation, I did a review on which latencies are acceptable for virtual environments. The goal of this review was to define requirements for our rowing scenario. I would appreciate feedback and comments on this review.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two main limitations of realism in virtual environments are a delayed response to user actions and desynchronized events. The cause for these undesired eff ects is the delay of the components and of the architecture as a whole. Examples for these speci fic delays are (Jacobs, Livingston, &amp;amp; State, 1997)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sensor delay:&lt;/strong&gt; the time until the sensor output signal reacts to the user action,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;network delay:&lt;/strong&gt; delays due to signal transportation,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;computational delay:&lt;/strong&gt; delays due to computational algorithms,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;rendering delay:&lt;/strong&gt; time elapsed while the graphics/sound engine is generating the resulting picture/sound,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;synchronization delay:&lt;/strong&gt; time in which data is waiting between stages without being processed,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;operating system delay:&lt;/strong&gt; Windows XP is not a real time system, therefore the execution of code can be delayed due to other threads or operating system activities, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;display/actuator delay:&lt;/strong&gt; the time between setting the input signal and the display&amp;#8217;s or actuator&amp;#8217;s reaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall time between a user action and the system response is de fined as end-to-end latency. Relative latency refers to the lag between di fferent modalities, e.g. between seeing an object crash on the ground and hearing the sound of this event. Jacobs et al. (1997) emphasized the importance of a small relative latency and suggested methods to minimize relative latency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One associated term is consistency which can be achieved by temporal and spatial synchronization of events, causality or ordering of events, and concurrency (multiple user interaction with one entity) (Delaney, Ward, &amp;amp; Mcloone, 2006). The authors discuss these terms for distributed interactive applications, for our single-user application concurrency does not apply. But temporal synchronization is an issue and therefore the relative latency must be minimized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of research exists on which latency is defensible for visual feedback in virtual reality environments. For visual feedback of hand motion, a end-to-end latency of greater than 100 ms restricted users to slow, careful movements (Friedmann, Starner, &amp;amp; Pentland, 1992). Experiments with head-mounted displays indicate that end-to-end latencies of 100 ms and 200 ms lead to an unstable perception of the environment (Allison, Harris, Jenkin, Jasiobedzka, &amp;amp; Zacher, 2001). Using head-mounted displays to display a pit room enviroment, Meehan, Razzaque, Whitton, and Brooks (2003) showed that latencies of 50 ms led to a higher self-reported sense of presence and a statistically higher change in heart rate than 90 ms. They also report that latencies beyond 120 ms produced unacceptable results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few results exist on auditory feedback. It is common knowledge among audio technicians, that latencies of 10 ms or less are needed for studio recordings. Friedmann et al. (1992) report 67 ms for their sound generation process and used a prediction method to synchronize sound output. More interesting for applications with multi-modal feedback are studies on cross-modal synchronization threshold. For audiovisual synchronization, Miner and Caudell (1998) report an average value of 175 ms and a minimal value of 100 ms. Their underlying explanation for this rather large value is that humans are used to some level of audiovisual desynchronization due to the di fferent propagation speeds of light and sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latencies of 20-30 ms or less are needed for music applications with a clearly-structured rhythm (Lago &amp;amp; Kon, 2004). Regarding haptic-auditory synchronization, the authors report that piano players face delays of 30-100 ms, depending on the volume and character of the note to be played. Regardless of this deviation, professional piano players are able to compensate this e ffect and get in synchrony. For rowing, higher values are certainly acceptable, as the overall movement takes a long time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regarding frame rates, the VR community demands at least 10 fps to provide an immersive experience to the user (Roy, Cruz-Neira, &amp;amp; Defanti, 1995). It is obvious that a low frame rate contributes to latency, as the projector may take some time before refreshing the image, even if the updated scene had already been rendered by the graphics pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Media Environments Become Real</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-02-05-when-media-environments-become-real/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2008 00:11:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-02-05-when-media-environments-become-real/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It all started with the alpenhorn. An elderly woman entered the auditory and played this traditional Swiss instrument. The view from the university to the mountains was also nice, although slightly cloudy on this particular day. I would rather see that version with the blue sky. And I would rather not see the bear living in captivity for the sake of being heraldic animal of the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The conference (see website) is not particularly interesting, the theme encompasses all kind of &lt;em&gt;media shifts&lt;/em&gt;, television, e-commerce, and virtual environments are all examples for that. Therefore, I as an engineer see myself to be on the margins of this conference. But there will be &lt;strong&gt;our&lt;/strong&gt; session on Wednesday on creating and measuring presence. So far psychologists and economists were on the forefront, stating their paradigms and theories without a single graph showing up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One exception was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.lsi.upc.edu/~melslater/&#34;&gt;Mel Slater&lt;/a&gt; from Universitat Politécnica de Catalunya in Barcelona. In his keynote speech on real actions in virtual environments he also expressed his dislike with the term presence, which is used and understood by many researchers, often in a contradictory sense. Therefore he used the terms &lt;em&gt;place illusion&lt;/em&gt; for some of the effects which he is investigating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first keynote lecture, Matthias Steinmann and Tanja Hackenbruch explained the concept of the reality switch as new paradigm. With this paradigm the old communication model (content, channel, recipient) was extended, explaining immersive effects of fictional media.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lokomat-Symposium 2006</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2006-10-06-lokomat-symposium-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 10:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2006-10-06-lokomat-symposium-2006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the second Lokomat Symposium featured the main talks regarding the Lokomat actuated gait orthosis. Actually the main scientists were all joined to present their latest research. To give you a short impression I will list the talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Speaker&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;David Reinkensmeyer (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Automating Arm Movement Training with T-WREX: Technical Overview and Clinical Data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Robert Riener (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Human-Centered Rehabilitation Robotics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Goffer (ISR)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;_Re_Walk: A Device for Overcoming Mobility Impairment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tobias Nef (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ARMin &amp;#8211; Robot-Aided Arm Therapy in Chronic Stroke&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Querry (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FES and Lokomat: Gait Synchronized Interventions with the Lokomat Driven Gait Orthosis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ken Hunt (UK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cardiopulmonary Assessment Protocols for Robot-Assisted Gait in Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pacheco (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spinal Plasticity in BWSTT: Evaluation of H-Reflexes in Spinal Cord Injury Patients during Stepping&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aschbacher (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comparing Gait Training in Patients after Stroke with Task-Oriented Physiotherapy or Robot-Assisted Gait Training with the Lokomat &amp;#8211; A Feasability Study&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Behrman (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Differential Effects of Robotically vs. Manually-Assisted Locomotor Training on Stepping Performance after Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Andreas Meyer (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;First Steps with the Pediatric Lokomat: Feasability of Robotic Assisted Locomotor Training in Children with Central Gait Impairment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Borggräfe (DE)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Automated Treadmill Training in Young Children with Cerebral Palsy with the Pediatric Lokomat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mogensen (DK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Effect of Robotic Treadmill Training in Patients with Cerebral Stroke&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not have a talk but was involved in some lab demos of the virtual environment extension of the Lokomat and the additional degrees of freedom (Gait3D). The audience was really impressed and especially for children the virtual reality enhancement triggered wild interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>