<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speakers on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/speakers/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speakers on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/speakers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Cortona Speakers</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-07-20-cortona-speakers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jul 2008 22:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-07-20-cortona-speakers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early September, I will again go to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cortona.ethz.ch&#34;&gt;Cortona week&lt;/a&gt;, which is offered by ETH Zurich. Now the list of lecture and workshop contributors seems complete and we &amp;ndash; the participants &amp;ndash; were asked to moderate sessions. So I went through the list of presenters to see, if any of these persons was particularly interesting for me. And I found interesting persons, but far too many of them. I will introduce four persons to give you an idea about the diversity of persons and topics in this one week in Cortona.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wolf Singer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wolf Singer is a German neuro scientist, he is well-known for his contributions to the debate of free will. His position is that there is no such thing as a free will. However, his talk will not circle around this question, it is about &lt;em&gt;Distributed Processing and Temporal Codes in Neuronal Networks&lt;/em&gt;. I am quite a fan of neural networks which are a mathematical model of neurons. In my early PhD times I envisioned to use neural networks for Lokomat control, but this plan was abondoned after negative feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tania Singer&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the same surname implies, Tania Singer is the daughter of Wolf Singer. She is professor at the University of Zurich and concerned with human social behaviour, especially empathy, fairness, altruism, and revenge. Her talk is about &lt;em&gt;Empathy from the Lens of Social Neuroscience&lt;/em&gt;. Interesting about her research is, that she uses physiological measurement methods like ECG, EEG , and skin conductance to investigate social phenomena. We use similar methods for our rowing study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anton Gunzinger&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He developed a parallel super computer in the 1990s and founded the company &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scs.ch/&#34;&gt;Super Computing Systems&lt;/a&gt; to bring it to the market. The company has now extended its product portfolio. The main obstacles on his way were not technological ones but marketing and financing. I am quite sure, his talk &lt;em&gt;Knowledge versus belief in entrepreneurship&lt;/em&gt; will touch some of the many lessons he had to learn as an entrepeneur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chungliang Al Huang&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chungliang Al Huang is a Tai Ji master and founder-president of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.livingtao.org/&#34;&gt;Living Tao Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. He will talk about &lt;em&gt;Living Tao: Ancient Wisdom for Modern Living&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lokomat-Symposium 2006</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2006-10-06-lokomat-symposium-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 10:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2006-10-06-lokomat-symposium-2006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the second Lokomat Symposium featured the main talks regarding the Lokomat actuated gait orthosis. Actually the main scientists were all joined to present their latest research. To give you a short impression I will list the talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Speaker&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;David Reinkensmeyer (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Automating Arm Movement Training with T-WREX: Technical Overview and Clinical Data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Robert Riener (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Human-Centered Rehabilitation Robotics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Goffer (ISR)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;_Re_Walk: A Device for Overcoming Mobility Impairment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tobias Nef (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ARMin &amp;#8211; Robot-Aided Arm Therapy in Chronic Stroke&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Querry (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FES and Lokomat: Gait Synchronized Interventions with the Lokomat Driven Gait Orthosis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ken Hunt (UK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cardiopulmonary Assessment Protocols for Robot-Assisted Gait in Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pacheco (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spinal Plasticity in BWSTT: Evaluation of H-Reflexes in Spinal Cord Injury Patients during Stepping&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aschbacher (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comparing Gait Training in Patients after Stroke with Task-Oriented Physiotherapy or Robot-Assisted Gait Training with the Lokomat &amp;#8211; A Feasability Study&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Behrman (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Differential Effects of Robotically vs. Manually-Assisted Locomotor Training on Stepping Performance after Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Andreas Meyer (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;First Steps with the Pediatric Lokomat: Feasability of Robotic Assisted Locomotor Training in Children with Central Gait Impairment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Borggräfe (DE)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Automated Treadmill Training in Young Children with Cerebral Palsy with the Pediatric Lokomat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mogensen (DK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Effect of Robotic Treadmill Training in Patients with Cerebral Stroke&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not have a talk but was involved in some lab demos of the virtual environment extension of the Lokomat and the additional degrees of freedom (Gait3D). The audience was really impressed and especially for children the virtual reality enhancement triggered wild interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>