<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Examination En on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/examination-en/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Examination En on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/examination-en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Doctoral examination &amp;#8211; passed!</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/2009/07/doctoral-examination-</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2009 17:28:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/2009/07/doctoral-examination-</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a little bit more than four years of research, this day saw my doctoral examination. It certainly wasn&amp;#8217;t my best presentation, but I made it through and passed the exam. My presentation lasted about 40&amp;thinsp;minutes, the questions and answers another 20&amp;thinsp;minutes. After one hour we were all asked to leave the room and only the professors remained in there to discuss my fate. After an endless time of fifteen minutes, I was called in the room and notified of the successful outcome. So it&amp;#8217;s over now. I feel relieved and very glad. I feel thankful towards the many people who supported me in this time, many of them were present at my defence talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;width: 510px&#34; class=&#34;wp-caption aligncenter&#34;&gt;
  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mwellner/3698565392/&#34;&gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Taking a question&#34; src=&#34;http://farm4.static.flickr.com/3628/3698565392_dc2faf1656.jpg&#34; title=&#34;Taking a question&#34; width=&#34;500&#34; height=&#34;355&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  
  &lt;p class=&#34;wp-caption-text&#34;&gt;
    Taking a question&lt;br /&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July 2005 I started on this journey, leaving behind Dresden and everything I knew. My research started with cooperative control strategies and the Lokomat, went on to virtual environments for gait rehabilitation, and finally brought me to the M&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt; Rowing Simulator. I covered quite some topics with rehabilitation robotics, virtual environments for rehabilitation, and sports simulation. I designed experiments, used Matlab and Simulink with high proficiency, programmed a lot in C++ and C#, used statistical methods, and supervised quite some students. Four years, which were characterised by learning and slow advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit:&lt;/strong&gt; I am not officially a &amp;ldquo;Dr. sc.&amp;rdquo; yet. This will be in October, after two ETH committees have approved and after I have handed in the printed and electronic versions for the library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>