<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iterative Learning on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/iterative-learning/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iterative Learning on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/iterative-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Article: Learning-Based Identification and Iterative Learning Control of Direct-Drive Robots</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-09-20-article-learning-based-identification-and-iterative-learning-control-of-direct-drive-robots/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 14:08:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-09-20-article-learning-based-identification-and-iterative-learning-control-of-direct-drive-robots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The article (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.citeulike.org/user/wellnair/article/316133&#34;&gt;bibliographic information&lt;/a&gt;) fits very much in what I am planning to do with the Lokomat. It is very well done in my opinion and a good base for my work. A robot with three degrees of freedom is used to investigate the proposed identification and control methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Abstract—A combination of model-based and iterative learning&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;control (ILC) is proposed as a method to achieve high-quality motion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;control of direct-drive robots in repetitive motion tasks.We include&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;both model-based and learning components in the total control&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;law, as their individual properties influence the performance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;of motion control. The model-based part of the controller compensates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;much of the nonlinear and coupled robot dynamics. A new&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;procedure for estimating the parameters of the rigid body model,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;implemented in this part of the controller, is used. This procedure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;is based on a batch-adaptive control algorithm that estimates the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;model parameters online. Information about the dynamics not covered&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by the rigid body model, due to flexibilities, is acquired experimentally,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;by identification. The models of the flexibilities are used&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in the design of the iterative learning controllers for the individual&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;joints. Use of the models facilitates quantitative prediction of performance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;improvement via ILC. The effectiveness of the combination&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;of the model-based and the iterative learning controllers is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;demonstrated in experiments on a spatial serial direct-drive robot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;with revolute joints.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>