<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rehabilitation Robotics on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/rehabilitation-robotics/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rehabilitation Robotics on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/rehabilitation-robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Science and Weblogs</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/2005/09/science-and-weblogs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2005 13:42:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/2005/09/science-and-weblogs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In my relentless search for articles in the field of rehabilitation robotics, I will publish some comments on excellent articles. With this I hope to help people who search relevant papers and also to find experts in the field for discussions and exchange. Everybody interested in the articles I found may take a look at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.citeulike.org/user/wellnair&#34;&gt;my articles at CiteULike&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My dissertation is about cooperative control strategies for the gait orthesis Lokomat. This field touches the following subject areas:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rehabilitation robotics (the big term),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control strategies in general,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variable structure control (swing and stance phase),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooperative control strategies (adaptive behaviour),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parameter identification (online if possible),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iterative learning,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patient model (so far the patient is seen as a disturbance) and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interface concept (in the end, therapists shall use all that with ease).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post is an experiment, since scientists are so far not using weblogs as a means of exchange and discussion. At least I don&amp;#8217;t know of any. But since I like the idea of weblogs I try to make a start in that and use it for scientific purposes. I will publish in English, since that enhances chances to be found by scientists all over the world.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>