<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Engineering on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/engineering/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Engineering on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Lokomat-Symposium 2006</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2006-10-06-lokomat-symposium-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2006 10:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2006-10-06-lokomat-symposium-2006/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today the second Lokomat Symposium featured the main talks regarding the Lokomat actuated gait orthosis. Actually the main scientists were all joined to present their latest research. To give you a short impression I will list the talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Speaker&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Title&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;David Reinkensmeyer (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Automating Arm Movement Training with T-WREX: Technical Overview and Clinical Data&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Robert Riener (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Human-Centered Rehabilitation Robotics&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Goffer (ISR)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;_Re_Walk: A Device for Overcoming Mobility Impairment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tobias Nef (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ARMin &amp;#8211; Robot-Aided Arm Therapy in Chronic Stroke&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Querry (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;FES and Lokomat: Gait Synchronized Interventions with the Lokomat Driven Gait Orthosis&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ken Hunt (UK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Cardiopulmonary Assessment Protocols for Robot-Assisted Gait in Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Pacheco (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Spinal Plasticity in BWSTT: Evaluation of H-Reflexes in Spinal Cord Injury Patients during Stepping&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Aschbacher (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Comparing Gait Training in Patients after Stroke with Task-Oriented Physiotherapy or Robot-Assisted Gait Training with the Lokomat &amp;#8211; A Feasability Study&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Behrman (USA)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Differential Effects of Robotically vs. Manually-Assisted Locomotor Training on Stepping Performance after Incomplete Spinal Cord Injury&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Andreas Meyer (CH)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;First Steps with the Pediatric Lokomat: Feasability of Robotic Assisted Locomotor Training in Children with Central Gait Impairment&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Borggräfe (DE)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Automated Treadmill Training in Young Children with Cerebral Palsy with the Pediatric Lokomat&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Mogensen (DK)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The Effect of Robotic Treadmill Training in Patients with Cerebral Stroke&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not have a talk but was involved in some lab demos of the virtual environment extension of the Lokomat and the additional degrees of freedom (Gait3D). The audience was really impressed and especially for children the virtual reality enhancement triggered wild interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einführungswoche in Zürich &amp;#8211; Introductory Week in Zurich</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-29-einfuhrungswoche-in-zurich-introductory-week-in-zurich/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2005 20:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-29-einfuhrungswoche-in-zurich-introductory-week-in-zurich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Diese Woche ist schnell vergangen. Ich verbrachte lange Tage im Labor und beschäftigte mich ausführlich mit dem Lokomat-Roboter und seiner vielfältigen Steuerung. Es ist zwar schwierig, sich in ein solch großes und komplexes Projekt innerhalb weniger Tage hineinzudenken, aber die wichtigsten Komponenten und Regelungsschleifen kenne ich jetzt. Sehr hilfreich war, dass für die Programmierung der Regelung &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.mathworks.com/products/simulink/&#34;&gt;MatLab Simulink&lt;/a&gt; verwendet wurde. Das ist eine grafische Art der Programmierung, die dem Ingenieursdenken sehr nahe kommt.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      This week really passed quickly. I spent some long days in the lab and got acquainted with the Lokomat robot and his various control concepts. It is difficult to really get into such a huge and complex project withing a few days, but I got a grip on the most important components and control loops. Very helpful was that the entire control program was created by &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.mathworks.com/products/simulink/&#34;&gt;MatLab SimuLink&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;#8217;s a graphical way of programming what is pretty close to how engineers think.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Martin and Michael are the two guys that have worked on the project, that I am bound to continue in July. Michael wrote a Diploma thesis and worked for half a year on the project after finishing that. He will continue in Munich with his PhD. Martin did his PhD on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hocoma.com/world/de/produkte/lokomat/&#34;&gt;Lokomat project&lt;/a&gt; in Munich and Zurich with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sms.hest.ethz.ch/the-group/team/robert-riener.html&#34;&gt;Prof. Riener&lt;/a&gt;. So he is the main expert with the system.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Martin und Michael arbeiten momentan am Projekt, beide werden jedoch bald aufhören. Michael schrieb seine Dipomarbeit zu einem Projektthema und hat auch danach noch ein halbes Jahr weitergemacht. Er wird als nächstes in München eine Doktorandenstelle antreten. Martin hat seine Dissertation zum &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hocoma.com/world/de/produkte/lokomat/&#34;&gt;Lokomat-Projekt&lt;/a&gt; mit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sms.hest.ethz.ch/the-group/team/robert-riener.html&#34;&gt;Prof. Riener&lt;/a&gt; in München und Zürich gemacht. Somit ist er der Hauptexperte des Systems.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>