<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publication on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/publication/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publication on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Journals for a publication of a rowing simulation study</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/2008/11/journals-for-a-publication-of-a-rowing-simulation-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2008 16:32:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/2008/11/journals-for-a-publication-of-a-rowing-simulation-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am recently searching for a journal to publish a study on audience pressure in our &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sms.hest.ethz.ch/research/current-research-projects/robot-assisted-training-in-sports.html&#34;&gt;M³ Rowing Simulator&lt;/a&gt;. This is rather difficult due to the multidisciplinary approach taken. We use a simulator with &lt;em&gt;virtual reality&lt;/em&gt; technology, conduct a &lt;em&gt;sports study&lt;/em&gt; on &lt;em&gt;psychological effects&lt;/em&gt; to investigate the feeling of &lt;em&gt;presence&lt;/em&gt; in the simulator. It&amp;#8217;s easy to get one or two of these topics combined in a journal description, but four of them are just too much. But nevertheless I would like to share which journals I found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mitpressjournals.org/pres&#34;&gt;Presence: Teleoperators and Virtual Environments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first academic journal for serious investigators of teleoperators and virtual environments, Presence is filled with stimulating material applicable to these advanced electromechanical and computer devices. Incorporating perspectives from physics to philosophy, Presence appeals to a wide audience &amp;#8211; particularly mechanical and electrical engineers concerned with teleoperators; those interested in virtual environments, including computer scientists, high-tech artists, and media people; and psychologists involved in the study of human-machine interfaces and sensorimotor/cognitive behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I published my first journal paper there. The review process was tough and long, but my paper was probably not that good in the beginning.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.liebertpub.com/products/product.aspx?pid=10&#34;&gt;CyberPsychology &amp;amp; Behavior&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This bimonthly peer-reviewed journal explores the impact of the Internet, multi-media and virtual reality on behavior and society. This journal is a &amp;#8220;must read&amp;#8221; for psychologists, psychiatrists, sociologists, educators, computer scientists, business executives and opinion-makers interested in the effects of interactive technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The focus is similar to that of Presence, although more on a general level with regards to interactive technologies and their implication on society.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computer Animation and Virtual Worlds&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the advent of very powerful PCs and high-end graphics cards, there has been an incredible development in Virtual Worlds, real-time computer animation and simulation, games. But at the same time, new and cheaper Virtual Reality devices have appeared allowing an interaction with these real-time Virtual Worlds and even with real worlds through Augmented Reality. Three-dimensional characters, especially Virtual Humans are now of an exceptional quality, which allows to use them in the movie industry. But this is only a beginning, as with the development of Artificial Intelligence and Agent technology, these characters will become more and more autonomous and even intelligent. They will inhabit the Virtual Worlds in a Virtual Life together with animals and plants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This would be good for a more general description of how we made the rowing scenario. Since we focused rather on conducting a sports study, this would probably not fit well.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pip.sagepub.com/&#34;&gt;Journal of Sports Engineering and Technology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journal of Sports Engineering and Technology is the publication of choice for authors seeking to disseminate original research findings related to the development or application of technology in sports.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;High quality output from engineering focused research activity is presented where the objective of the work undertaken was to enhance user performance (fitness, skill, comfort, etc.), reduce incidence and severity of injury, increase participation rates, promote participation, or enhance the spectator experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;They are quite new (one issue so far).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tandf.co.uk/journals/titles/02640414.asp&#34;&gt;Journal of Sports Sciences&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journal of Sports Sciences publishes articles of a high standard on various aspects of the sports sciences covering a number of disciplinary bases, including anatomy, biochemistry, biomechanics, psychology, sociology, as well as ergonomics, kinanthropometry and other interdisciplinary perspectives. In addition to reports of research, review articles and book reviews are published. The emphasis of the Journal is on the human sciences, broadly defined, applied to sport and exercise. Besides experimental work in human responses to exercise, the subjects covered will include technologies such as the design of sports equipment and playing facilities, research in training, selection, performance prediction or modification, and stress reduction or manifestation. Manuscripts dealing with original investigations of exercise, validation of technological innovations in sport or comprehensive reviews of topics relevant to the scientific study of sport will be considered for publication.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journal presents research findings in the growing area of exercise and sports sciences to an international audience. The readership for this journal is varied and ranges from academic research workers to professionals in recreation, sports coaching and training.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.humankinetics.com/jsep/journalAbout.cfm&#34;&gt;Journal of Sport &amp;amp; Exercise Psychology&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Journal of Sport &amp;amp; Exercise Psychology (JSEP) publishes research articles by leading world scholars that explore the interactions between psychology and exercise and sport performance, editorials about contemporary issues in the field, abstracts of current research on sport and exercise psychology, and book reviews. JSEP is an official publication of the North American Society for the Psychology of Sport and Physical Activity (NASPSPA).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.springer.com/new+%26+forthcoming+titles+(default)/journal/12283&#34;&gt;Sports Engineering&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sports Engineering is an international journal publishing original papers on the application of engineering and science to sport. The journal intends to fill the niche area which lies between classical engineering and sports science and aims to bridge the gap between the analysis of the equipment and of the athlete. Areas of interest include the mechanics and dynamics of sport, the analysis of movement, instrumentation, equipment design, surface interaction, materials and modelling. These topics may be applied to technology in almost any sport. The journal will be of particular interest to Engineering, Physics, Mathematics and Sports Science Departments and will act as a forum where research, industry and the sports sector can exchange knowledge and innovative ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PRESENCE publishes Lokomat article</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/2008/10/presence-publishes-lokomat-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2008 11:54:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/2008/10/presence-publishes-lokomat-article/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At last! 1.5 years after starting to write, the article &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mitpressjournals.org/doi/abs/10.1162/pres.17.5.512&#34;&gt;Evaluation of Visual and Auditory Feedback in Virtual Obstacle Walking&lt;/a&gt; has been published by Presence. This is the final step, now it&amp;#8217;s really over. I hope that my next publications will go a little bit smoother, but you never know what reviewers you get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Mathias Wellner, ­Audrey Schaufelberger,­ Joachim v. Zitzewitz, Robert Riener&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Title:&lt;/strong&gt; Evaluation of Visual and Auditory Feedback in Virtual Obstacle Walking&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Journal:&lt;/strong&gt; Presence: Teleoperators and Virtual Environments&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; This paper describes evaluation experiments for visual and auditory feedback in a virtual obstacle walking scenario. Two studies with healthy subjects were carried out using the actuated gait orthosis Lokomat. Controlled factors for the visual feedback experiment were three different perspectives and 2D/3D vision. In the auditory feedback experiment, controlled factors were rhythmic distance feedback and gradual foot clearance feedback. For the visual and auditory feedback experiments, outcome was assessed with task-specific performance parameters and questionnaires. Results for visual feedback indicate that the chosen side perspective is superior to behind and ego perspectives. It is also shown that 3D vision does not reduce the number of obstacle hits compared to 2D vision. Furthermore, it is demonstrated that adding continuous auditory feedback made subjects walk faster compared to the exclusive use of visual feedback. Subjects rated auditory distance feedback as more helpful than auditory foot clearance feedback. Therefore, we suggest using side perspective and auditory feedback on obstacle distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next publication is already in the queue and will target one study with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sms.hest.ethz.ch/research/current-research-projects/robot-assisted-training-in-sports.html&#34;&gt;M3 rowing simulator&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proof for publication has arrived</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/2008/08/proof-for-publication-has-arrived/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2008 18:32:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/2008/08/proof-for-publication-has-arrived/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After nearly four months, I got the proofs of my publication yesterday. The proof is already pretty close to the article and is the last chance for changes. But I found only subtle mistakes in the proof, some images appeared much bigger than I had intended them to be. In two months, the article will appear in PRESENCE.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paper accepted</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/2008/04/paper-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2008 19:27:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/2008/04/paper-accepted/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, we got it through! I now can also reveal that the scientific journal of my choice was &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mitpressjournals.org/pres&#34;&gt;Presence&lt;/a&gt;, published by MIT Press. It was a long process, which raised my awareness of scientific language enormously. However, I am not sure whether that is a good thing. I now tend to get on other people&amp;#8217;s nerves when they write something and ask for my opinion on that. There are so many mistakes and inconsistencies to discover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wonder if there is one written form to express an idea adequately. One form which has exactly the right length. And I wonder, how many iterations it takes to get to that form.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resubmission</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/2008/01/resubmission/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Jan 2008 17:07:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/2008/01/resubmission/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I did it again. I revised my paper completely and resubmitted it to the journal of my choice. Compared to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mwellner.de/2007/08/29/paper-submission/&#34;&gt;original submission&lt;/a&gt;, the haptic evaluation part was removed, a structural reorganization took place, and many improvements in argumentation and plausibility were added. So now it&amp;#8217;s in the editorial pipeline again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; This paper describes evaluation experiments for visual and auditory feedback in a virtual obstacle walking scenario. Two studies with healthy subjects were carried out using the actuated gait orthosis Lokomat. Controlled factors for the visual feedback experiment were three different perspectives and 2D/3D vision. In the auditory feedback experiment, controlled factors were rhythmic distance feedback and gradual foot clearance feedback. For visual and auditory feedback experiments, outcome was assessed with task-specific performance parameters and questionnaires. Results for visual feedback indicate that the chosen side perspective is superior to behind and ego perspectives. It is also shown that 3D vision does not reduce the number of obstacle hits compared to 2D vision. Furthermore, it is demonstrated that the addition of continuous auditory feedback makes subjects walk faster compared to the exclusive use of visual feedback. Therefore, we suggest to use the side perspective and auditory feedback on obstacle distance, which was rated most helpful by the subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>