<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Matlab on mathias wellner</title>
    <link>http://www.mwellner.de/tags/matlab/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Matlab on mathias wellner</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>de-de</language>
    <atom:link href="http://www.mwellner.de/tags/matlab/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a participant database</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2009-04-24-creating-a-participant-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2009 18:00:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2009-04-24-creating-a-participant-database/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The initial intention was to keep track of those people who have participated in one of our rowing studies. The second goal was to keep track of how our raw data is organised. Therefore, I designed a relational database with MS Access. In this article I will focus on general database design issues and how to access the database with Matlab. You could use any other &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Relational_database_management_system&#34;&gt;relational database management system&lt;/a&gt;, which is compatible to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/SQL&#34;&gt;SQL standard&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A nice side-effect of such a database is their possible integration in Matlab. We can get the names of all participants of a certain study and analyse their data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database structure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first relation contains the &lt;em&gt;participant&lt;/em&gt; information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ID [primary key]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LastName&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;FirstName&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gender&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;BirthDate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CategoryID [foreign key]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rowing skill of the participant should be identified in a repetible way, therefore a separate relation contains all possible skill levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Category&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ID [primary key]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Label&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next obvious relation describes our studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Study&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ID [primary key]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Label&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsible person(s)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data folder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We now need a connection between participants and studies, including the possibility of several runs. This is implemented with the relation &lt;em&gt;Participant takes part&lt;/em&gt;. Note that the primary key is a combination of ParticipantID, StudyID, and RunNumber to prevent double-insertion of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ParticipantID [primary key, foreign key]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;StudyID [primary key, foreign key]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RunDate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RunNumber [primary key]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DataValid&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For our &lt;em&gt;raw variables&lt;/em&gt; (oar angles, seat position, physiological data) we also define a relation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Id [primary key]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our raw data comes in a huge matrix, where each row contains the recording at one specific point in time and each column one raw variable. The assignment of raw data to columns can differ for different studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Raw variable is in column&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RawVariableID [primary key, foreign key]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;StudyID [primary key, foreign key]&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Column (in xPC output log)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database access with Matlab&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can now use the power of SQL statements to query the database for a specific participant. As a more complex example, I will demonstrate how to get all participants of one study.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following Matlab code builds an SQL query and executes it with an existing database connection (&lt;code&gt;database&lt;/code&gt; command). You need to define an ODBC connection first, see the Matlab documentation for more details on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
% define parts of SQL statement&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
study = &#39;&#39;&#39;Study1&#39;&#39;&#39;; % define study, add addition &#39;&#39; because of spaces&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
columns = &#39;LastName, FirstName&#39;; % define columns for selection&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
from = &#39;Participant p, TakesPart t, Study s&#39;; % define tables for selection&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
where = [&#39;p.ID = t.ParticipantID AND s.ID = t.StudyID AND s.Label = &#39;, study]; % define inner join conditions&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
order = &#39;LastName, FirstName&#39;; % define order of results&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
% combine parts to SQL query&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
query = sprintf(&#39;SELECT %s FROM %s WHERE %s ORDER BY %s&#39;, columns, from, where, order);&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
curs = exec(DatabaseConnection, query); % execute SQL query&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
curs = fetch(curs); % fetch data in same cursor structure&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
curs.Data&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
close(curs);&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The created query is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;SELECT LastName, FirstName FROM Participant p, TakesPart t, Study s WHERE p.ID = t.ParticipantID AND s.ID = t.StudyID AND s.Label = &#39;Study1&#39; ORDER BY LastName, FirstName&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I showed how to design a participant database and query it with Matlab.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling huge amounts of raw data with Matlab</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2009-04-07-handling-huge-amounts-of-raw-data-with-matlab/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2009 12:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2009-04-07-handling-huge-amounts-of-raw-data-with-matlab/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Matlab workspace is limited in size, depending on your system. We reached the workspace limit with a rowing study (10 participants, 1&amp;thinsp;kHz sampling rate, 20 variables, 10 minutes duration). Although the extracted data fits very well in the workspace, the raw data does not. Therefore, a solution is needed with fast access to specific variables. This is needed for feature extraction and later display of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Approach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three approaches were used to solve this problem,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;using a relational database (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mathworks.com/products/database/&#34;&gt;database toolbox&lt;/a&gt;),&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;storing the raw data in one workspace with multiple variables, and&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;storing each raw data variable in one workspace.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each approach was implemented and the access time to retrieve one variable was the goal criterium. The sample data set had 555k entries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The relational database system PostgreSQL was tested successfully but could not be used for large amounts of data. Already the storage of one data set took more than half an hour, and after a certain size an error occured with limited heap size. It seems that the driver implementation for Matlab does not allow big amounts of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The implementation with the Matlab workspaces was much possible, interestingly single workspaces proved more efficient than one combined workspace (only the desired variable was loaded from the combined workspace).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; clear all&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; tic;load combined_workspace variable; toc&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Elapsed time is 9.0 seconds.&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; clear all&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt; tic; load variable_workspace; toc&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
Elapsed time is 1.1 seconds.&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using single workspaces for every variable is the fastest way of accessing huge amounts of raw data. The usage of a relational database system poses additional burdens, but it seems appropriate for smaller amounts of data (participants, block features, extracted data). The advantage over defining all these things in Matlab variables is the powerful SQL syntax for retrieving particular chunks of data. And in addition, the definition of primary keys and other conditions prevents you from inserting dublicate or faulty data in the database.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This!</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2009-03-11-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2009 21:52:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2009-03-11-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ich schreibe. An meiner Diss. Ich habe sie &lt;strong&gt;This!&lt;/strong&gt; genannt, das klingt so wie Diss und erinnert mich an Peter Gabriels Album &lt;a href=&#34;http://petergabriel.com/discography/release/So/&#34;&gt;So&lt;/a&gt;, ein Weihnachtsgeschenk meiner Schwester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ich schreibe. Über die Ergebnisse der Ruderstudie mit Wettbewerbern. Teilnehmer 1 hat reagiert, und das deutlich. Man sieht es an den Graphen, den Prunkstücken dieses Kapitels. Es lässt sich so viel aussagen mit einem Graphen. Dann brauche ich auch weniger zu schreiben. Es springt dem Leser dann ins Auge. Aber nur, wenn der Graph gut gemacht ist und in sich das Studiendesign, die Einzelergebnisse, die Durchschnittswerte pro Block mit Standardabweichungen und am besten noch die Schlussfolgerungen in sich vereint und dabei nicht unübersichtlich wird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ich schreibe. Ein &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Matlab&#34;&gt;Matlab&lt;/a&gt;-Skript zum Zeichnen eines Graphen. Es wird immer länger, Zeile um Zeile kommt hinzu. Zuerst waren da nur die blauen Datenpunkte, etwas chaotisch zeigten sie den Wert einer Variablen (zum Beispiel der Maximalkraft) für jeden Ruderschlag an, und das für die gesamte Rennstrecke von 2000&amp;thinsp;m. Aber das reicht nicht, man muss noch die Blöcke sehen. Die neutralen Blöcke, in denen die Gegner nichts machen und die Gegner-Blöcke, in denen die gegnerischen Boote attackieren oder zurückfallen. Senkrechte rote Linien für die Blockgrenzen, das ist schon mal ein Anfang. Aber wie kann man die Gegner-Blöcke noch durch eine andere Hintergrundfarbe hervorheben? Zuerst versuche ich es mit dem Befehl patch, damit kann man beliebige Polygone zu einem Graphen hinzufügen. Aber dieser verdeckt die Randlinien. Die Lösung bringt dann der Befehl &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mathworks.com/access/helpdesk/help/techdoc/ref/image.html&#34;&gt;image&lt;/a&gt;, ein entsprechend den Blöcken definiertes Bild dient als Hintergrund des Graphen. Blaue Punkte auf dezent hervorgehobenen Blöcken, getrennt durch vertikale rote Linien. Schön wäre noch, bei jedem Block den Mittelwert der Variablen und die Standardabweichung einzuzeichnen. Mit horizontalen, schwarzen, dicken Linien kommen die Mittelwerte hinzu, mit dünneren Linien, die sich nach oben und unten strecken, die Standardabweichungen. Jetzt noch zuschneiden auf die richtige Größe, damit es ohne weitere Verarbeitung in die Diss eingefügt werden kann.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ich schreibe. Mit &lt;a href=&#34;https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/LaTeX&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt;-Befehlen füge ich die Graphen ein. Und beschrifte noch die Blöcke, damit klar ist, welche neutral und welche durch Aktivitäten der Gegner geprägt sind. Dies in allen Graphen. Diese Wiederholung einer ähnlichen Aufgabe, in der sich nur die Reihenfolge der Konditionen verändert, schreit nach einem Makro. So weit ist es mit mir gekommen, das Dokument hat sich in eine Struktur verwandelt, welche stets verbessert werden kann. Ich sehe überall Struktur, die Ähnlichkeit von Abschnitten, die Möglichkeit, etwas eleganter zu lösen, mit weniger Redundanzen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ich schreibe. 85 Seiten ist &lt;strong&gt;This!&lt;/strong&gt; jetzt stark. Es ist nicht mehr viel, das Ziel ist in Sicht. Dann wird die erste Fassung vollendet sein.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using xPC COM API and Visual C#</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-04-05-using-xpc-com-api-and-visual-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2008 16:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2008-04-05-using-xpc-com-api-and-visual-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This entry is for those who want to control an xPC target computer with a program written in C#. I personally did not find any example how to do this, the documentation provides an example using Visual Basic, but I found a simpler way. I do only use the xPC COM API (which must be included as reference in the project) and not the model COM interface. I think this is easier because you don&amp;#8217;t have to reinsert the model reference if you recompile it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The example here is a very simple one. I just needed to connect to the target, load the application, and register one signal, which I need to access. Please note that you need to insert a gain element with value 1 to register a signal (Target.GetSignalIdx).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre name=&#34;code&#34; class=&#34;c#&#34;&gt;using System;
using System.Collections.Generic;
using System.Linq;
using System.Text;
using XPCAPICOMLib;

namespace ProjectNamespace
{
    class XPC_COM
    {
        private xPCProtocol Protocol;  // from XPCAPICOMLib
        private xPCTarget Target;      // from XPCAPICOMLib
        private int SignalID;   // signal ID for one signal

        public XPC_COM()  // constructor for XPC_COM object
        {
            // initialize protocol and target objects
            Protocol = new xPCProtocol();
            Target = new xPCTarget();
            // establish connection to target
            Protocol.Init();
            Protocol.TcpIpConnect(&#34;192.168.0.1&#34;, &#34;22222&#34;);
            // load application
            Target.Init(Protocol);
            Target.LoadApp(&#34;folder name&#34;, &#34;model name&#34;);
            // find signal id
            SignalID = Target.GetSignalIdx(&#34;signal name&#34;);
        }

        ~XPC_COM() // destructor for XPC_COM object
        {
            // close connection to xPC target
            Protocol.Close();
        }

        public int isAppRunning()
        {
            return Target.IsAppRunning();
        }

        public void startApp()
        {
            Target.StartApp();
        }

        public void stopApp()
        {
            Target.StopApp();
        }

        public double getLength()
        {
            return Target.GetSignal(SignalID);
        }

    }
}
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Matlab &amp;#8212; Intuitiv und einfach?</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-29-matlab-intuitiv-und-einfach/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2005 23:12:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-29-matlab-intuitiv-und-einfach/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bislang war ich ja doch ein erklärter Verfechter von Matlab als einer einfachen Programmierwprache, mit der man schnell zu Ergebnissen kommt. Doch heute las ich die Seite eines erklärten Gegners solcher einfachen Skript-Sprachen. Er argumentiert, dass durch die vielen Vereinfachungen &amp;#8211; als da wären:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Variablentypen müssen nicht deklariert werden, sondern ergeben sich beim ersten Aufruf,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatische Umwandlung von Skalarwerten in Matritzen und&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Skalarwerte und Vektoren sind Spezialfälle von Matritzen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wegwerf-Programme entstünden, die nicht mehr lesbar seien und für größere Projekte ungeeignet wären. Nun, da bin ich ja gespannt, ob ich mich nach einiger Zeit seiner Kritik anschließe. Die Frage stellt sich halt, welche Alternativen zur Verfügung stehen. Alles in C zu programmieren ist halt nicht wirklich toll und erfordert lange Einarbeitungszeiten.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einführungswoche in Zürich &amp;#8211; Introductory Week in Zurich</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-29-einfuhrungswoche-in-zurich-introductory-week-in-zurich/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2005 20:37:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-29-einfuhrungswoche-in-zurich-introductory-week-in-zurich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Diese Woche ist schnell vergangen. Ich verbrachte lange Tage im Labor und beschäftigte mich ausführlich mit dem Lokomat-Roboter und seiner vielfältigen Steuerung. Es ist zwar schwierig, sich in ein solch großes und komplexes Projekt innerhalb weniger Tage hineinzudenken, aber die wichtigsten Komponenten und Regelungsschleifen kenne ich jetzt. Sehr hilfreich war, dass für die Programmierung der Regelung &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.mathworks.com/products/simulink/&#34;&gt;MatLab Simulink&lt;/a&gt; verwendet wurde. Das ist eine grafische Art der Programmierung, die dem Ingenieursdenken sehr nahe kommt.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      This week really passed quickly. I spent some long days in the lab and got acquainted with the Lokomat robot and his various control concepts. It is difficult to really get into such a huge and complex project withing a few days, but I got a grip on the most important components and control loops. Very helpful was that the entire control program was created by &lt;a href=&#34;http://de.mathworks.com/products/simulink/&#34;&gt;MatLab SimuLink&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;#8217;s a graphical way of programming what is pretty close to how engineers think.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Martin and Michael are the two guys that have worked on the project, that I am bound to continue in July. Michael wrote a Diploma thesis and worked for half a year on the project after finishing that. He will continue in Munich with his PhD. Martin did his PhD on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hocoma.com/world/de/produkte/lokomat/&#34;&gt;Lokomat project&lt;/a&gt; in Munich and Zurich with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sms.hest.ethz.ch/the-group/team/robert-riener.html&#34;&gt;Prof. Riener&lt;/a&gt;. So he is the main expert with the system.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Martin und Michael arbeiten momentan am Projekt, beide werden jedoch bald aufhören. Michael schrieb seine Dipomarbeit zu einem Projektthema und hat auch danach noch ein halbes Jahr weitergemacht. Er wird als nächstes in München eine Doktorandenstelle antreten. Martin hat seine Dissertation zum &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hocoma.com/world/de/produkte/lokomat/&#34;&gt;Lokomat-Projekt&lt;/a&gt; mit &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sms.hest.ethz.ch/the-group/team/robert-riener.html&#34;&gt;Prof. Riener&lt;/a&gt; in München und Zürich gemacht. Somit ist er der Hauptexperte des Systems.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Einarbeitung in Zürich &amp;#8212; Adjustment in Zurich</title>
      <link>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-26-einarbeitung-in-zurich-adjustment-in-zurich/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2005 12:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.mwellner.de/post/2005-04-26-einarbeitung-in-zurich-adjustment-in-zurich/</guid>
      <description>&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      In einer Woche werde ich in einer Art Crash-Kurs an die technischen Einzelheiten des Projekts herangeführt. Sämtliche Steuerungsprogramme sind in Simulink umgesetzt, die Bedienoberfläche ist in LabView gehalten. Damit kann man sehr schön in Strukturen denken und programmieren und muss sich nicht durch tausende Zeilen Code wühlen. Aber dennoch, durch allerlei Forschungsprojekte ist eine Menge zusammengekommen, was sich nicht unbedingt auf den ersten Blick erschliesst.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      In one week I will be introduced to the technical details of the research project. The control program is done completely in SimuLink, all the elements of the user interface were created by LabView. The advantage of both programs is that you can think in structures and don&amp;#8217;t have to look through thousands of code lines. But despite of that the project is quite huge and therefore it is not that easy to get all that at the first glimpse.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Mit Hilfe des &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hospitalityclub.org&#34;&gt;Hospitylity Club&lt;/a&gt; habe ich einen netten Gastgeber gefunden, bei dem ich für die Woche unterkommen kann. Sein Mitbewohner muss zum Militär, so dass ich dessen Zimmer in dieser Zeit nutzen kann. Perfekt, so habe ich sogar ein eigenes Bett und muss nicht auf der Iso-Matte schlafen!
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hospitalityclub.org&#34;&gt;Hospitality Club&lt;/a&gt; I was able to find a nice host for the entire week. His flat mate has to do military service, so I can use his room. That&amp;#8217;s perfect, I even have my own bed and don&amp;#8217;t have to sleep on the camping matress.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;tr&gt;
    &lt;td&gt;
      Als ich ankam, fand gerade eine Besprechung mit allen Labor-Mitarbeitern statt. Das heisseste Thema war dann die Keks-Finanzierung, eine halbe Stunde lang wurden verschiedene Vorschläge angebracht, verworfen, bis es dann am Ende zur Abstimmung kam.
    &lt;/td&gt;
    
    &lt;td&gt;
      When I arrived here on Monday morning, there happened to be a meeting with all the people involved with tha lab. The hottest topic was how to finance the cookies, since the old model did not work in some people&amp;#8217;s opinion. For half a hour several proposals were discussed until finally a vote was taken.
    &lt;/td&gt;
  &lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>